Guide to the Study Commission on Governance, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Study Commission on Governance, Yale University, records
1969-1972
RU 530
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.25
The records consist of minutes, reports, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Yale University Study Commission on Governance.
Yale University. Study Commission on Governance
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records on Yale committees.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of minutes, reports, and correspondence documenting the activities of the Yale University Study Commission on Governance.
Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Study Commission on Governance
- Records of David Maslyn, 1969-1972; Accession 1972-A-006
  - Minutes, reports, correspondence, 1969 September - 1971 April (Box 1, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Preliminary reports
    - Part I, 1971 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Part II, 1971 January 30 (Box 1)
  - Final report, 1971 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Research materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - University priorities, 1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Working papers, 1962-1971; Accession 1991-A-088
  - Study Commission on Governance
    - Election of Representatives, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rosters, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Summer Rosters, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Resignations, Appointments, etc., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Organization and Composition, 1969 Fall (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Plenary Session Meetings, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Mr. Burrell's Original Minutes, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Extra Copies of Minutes, Memos, etc., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Rough Drafts of Minutes, Notices, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Guest Speakers, Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - General Administration, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Financial, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Business Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Office Record, Payroll Forms, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Summer Employment, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stock and Service Requests, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Mr. Hackman's Questionnaire, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Commission Members' Suggested Revisions, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Working Groups: Breakdown, Preference, Slips, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Executive Committee Minutes, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Executive Committee Reports, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence and Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Executive Committee Priority Reports, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Final Drafts of Governance Report of Executive Committee, 1971 February (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Final Reports of Working Groups to Executive Committee, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Committee of University Priorities: Minutes, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Committee on Priorities: Correspondence, Reports, etc., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Committee on External Relations, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Committee on University Procedures: Documents, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Committee on University Procedures: Minutes, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Committee on University Procedures: Extra Copies, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Committee on Academic Affairs: Minutes, etc., 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Committee on University Services, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34 - 35)
    - Yale Medical School, 1979 July (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dominguez Commission
    - Index to Dominguez Files, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Minutes, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Proposals, Memos, Reports, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Notes on Models of University Governance, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Notes on Participation in the Governance of Yale University, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Openness, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Background, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Enormous Room Reports, 1969 Fall (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Tape of Public Meeting of the Dominguez Commission, 1969 July 14 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Triffin Plan: Participation, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "A Bill of Obligations for Yale University", 1968 October (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Yale: Union and Student Demands, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Coeducation, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - President Brewster: Public Statements, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence to Kingman Brewster, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Report of the President, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Yale University Reports, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Yale: Faculty Handbook, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Yale College: A Handbook for the Director of Undergraduate Studies, 1968 May (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Report of the Commission on Alumni Affairs, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Alumni, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Discipline Committee's Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Committee of Fifteen Interim Report on the Causes of the Recent Crisis, 1969 July (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - University Council Bylaws, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Copies of Charter, Legislation and Bylaws of Yale Corporation, 1932-1970 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Yale Corporation: Bylaws and Regulations, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - "The Making of a Corporation", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Yale Daily News: The Corporation, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Graduate School Information, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Art and Architecture, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Yale School of Medicine, 1969 March (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Yale University Institute of Social Science material, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Yale University Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Vassar-Yale: Report from the Joint Study Committee, 1967 September (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - General Information on Governance, 1960-1970 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Excerpts from the Proceedings of the Conference on Governance of Universities: Rights and Responsibilities: A Study in Academic Ethics, 1968 November (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - University Education in General, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Model Code of Procedure for Academic Freedom and Tenure Cases, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - AAUP: Other Universities
    - Index of Other Universities Material, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Berkeley, University of California at, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Brandeis University, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Boston University, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Columbia University, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 81 - 83)
    - Cornell University, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Hamilton College, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Harvard University, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Princeton University, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Quinnipiac College, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Stanford University, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - State College of Iowa, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - State University of New York, undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Tulane University, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1962-1969 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Washington State University, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Wesleyan University, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Western Michigan University, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 97)